

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Javascript
- Angular
- AngularJS
- ReactIS
- NodeJS / Express
- Socket.io
- Typescript
- MongoDB
- Algolia
- HTML / CSS / SCSS / LESS / SASS
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- REST
- Cordova / Ionic
- Python / Pytorch for ML

DEVELOPMENT TOOLS

- Git
- Jira
- Azure
- MongoDB Compass
- AWS
- SonarCloud
- Jenkins

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Reliable and professional
- Organised
- Efficient communicator
- Team player
- Fast learner Motivated
- Curious

LANGUAGES

- English
- Romanian

CONTACT

Phone: +40 730 799 252 Email: silviualexd@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/SilviuDinu

SILVIU DINU

ABOUT

Hi, I'm Silviu, a 27-year-old Senior Software Enginner with over 3 years of experience in web development technologies such as React, Angular and NodeJS. Driven by curiosity, I'm constantly on the hunt for new projects that push my skill set further. Proactive and optimistic, I thrive when faced with challenges, always approaching them with a solution-oriented mindset.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

LONDON STOCK EXCHANGE GROUP, Bucharest I Feb. 2024 - Present

- In my role as a Senior Full Stack Developer, I focus on developing cuttingedge software solutions that simplify financial operations and elevate the user experience. My contributions are central to equipping our users with dependable and effective financial tools
- Working with tools like: React, NodeJS

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

COGNIZANT, Bucharest | Oct. 2022 - Feb. 2024

- As a Full Stack Developer in my current project, I not only engineer scalable and efficient software solutions, but also contribute strategic business ideas aimed at boosting customer revenue.
- · Working with tools like: React, NodeJS, MongoDB, AEM, Algolia

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

EPAM SYSTEMS, Bucharest I Oct. 2021 - Oct. 2022

- Consistently delivering superior quality services to our valued clients
- Working with tools like: Angular, AngularJS, NodeJS, Jira, Ionic, Cordova

CONSULTANT - MIDDLE FRONTEND DEVELOPER

DELOITTE DIGITAL, Bucharest | Feb. 2020 - Oct. 2021

- Proactively collaborating with clients to deliver premium services and consultancy, ensuring excellence in my contributions
- Working with tools like: Angular, AngularJS, React, SCSS, Jira

JUNIOR PROGRAMMER - TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER

THEMEISLE, Bucharest | Jul. 2018 - Feb. 2020

- Assisting clients in developing robust WordPress websites
- Solving/reporting bugs and debugging (PHP, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL)

CERTIFICATIONS

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED - AZURE FUNDAMENTALS

18 Sep. 2023 View credential

MONGODB - SI ASSOCIATE CERTIFICATION

18 Jun. 2023 View credential



PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Javascript
- Angular
- AngularJS
- ReactJS
- NodeJS / Express
- Socket.io
- Typescript
- MongoDB
- Algolia
- HTML / CSS / SCSS / LESS / SASS
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- REST
- Cordova / Ionic
- Python / Pytorch for ML
- Php

DEVELOPMENT TOOLS

- Git
- Jira
- Azure
- MongoDB Compass
- AWS
- SonarCloud
- lenkins

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Reliable and professional
- Organised
- Efficient communicator
- Team player
- Fast learner
- Motivated
- Curious

LANGUAGES

- English
- Romanian

CONTACT

Phone: +40 730 799 252 Email: silviualexd@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/SilviuDinu

EDUCATION

MASTER'S DEGREE IN ADVANCED SIGNAL PROCESSING

Faculty of Automatic Control and Computer Science, University POLITEHNICA of Bucharest | 2020 - 2022

 Research work on how Machine Learning can help Medicine: <u>View on</u> ReasearchGate

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN SYSTEMS ENGINEERING

Faculty of Automatic Control and Computer Science, University POLITEHNICA of Bucharest | 2016 - 2020

PROJECTS / COURSES

RESUME / PRESENTATION WEBSITE

A presentation app built for myself containing information like: resume, who am I and what I do, hobbies and more.

Used tools: Angular 12, Angular Router, Angular Material, Typescript, RxJS https://silviualex.com/about-me

DISEASE PREDICTOR

I architected, fine-tuned, and validated a Neural Network that takes medical symptoms as input and forecasts the most likely corresponding disease. This model serves as the central element of a Flask-based backend server, which I also developed. This server is part of a custom API designed to interact with a frontend, accepting symptom data and returning the predicted disease.

Used tools: Python, PyTorch, Machine Learning, Flask, REST APIs, Data Science

REACT WEATHER APP

A weather app built with React and Express which enables the user to search the weather in certain cities around the world. The app automatically detects your location and displays the weather information that is most relevant to you.

Used tools: React Hooks, React router, Express, REST APIs, Typescript, MongoDB https://forecast-report.com/

WEB SOCKETS CHAT

A web chat application built with React on the FE and socket.io running on the BE. Users can connect to the chat room and exchange messages with each other.

Used tools: React Hooks, Node.JS, Websockets, Socket.io, Typescript https://github.com/SilviuDinu/web-sockets-chat

URL SHORTENER

A web app created with Vue.JS and Express that enables the users to create shortURLs.

Used tools: Vue.JS, Express, MongoDB https://slv.lol/